# PETER BAGGETTA B.ENG

(416)854-5405 \phi peter.baggetta@gmail.com \phi github.com/PeterBaggetta \phi https://peterbaggetta.com/

#### **PROFILE**

As a recent Computer Engineering graduate with up-to-date knowledge and strong problem-solving abilities, I am a dedicated and dependable worker. My diverse experience in office settings and development has honed my clear communication skills and enables me to collaborate effectively in various work environments as I pursue my P.Eng. license.

# SKILLS & **CERTIFICATIONS**

- 4 years Git, GitHub & GitLab
- 4 years HTML & CSS, C & C++
- 4 years MATLAB & Simulink & R
- 3 years Python, Java & JavaScript
- 3 years Verilog, VHDL & assembly
- 3 years NodeJS, React & React Native
- 2 years PHP, SQL & NoSQL, Spring Boot, React, Junit, Jira, Figma & Cloudflare
- 1 year Microsoft Azure, Docker, Bitbucket, Cloudinary & SwiftUI

- AWS Solutions Architect Knowledge Badge (AWS Cloud Technologies)
- Quartus, Vivado, Cadence, & Xilinx
- Windows, Mac & Linux experience
- FreeRTOS, I2C, SPI, ARM Cortex
- FPGAs and SoC Device (ARM & x86) programming in VHDL, Verilog, MIPS/ARM assembly & C
- Keil & IAR Compiler workflow

# **PROJECTS**

#### **AES Encryption Coprocessor in CBC Mode**

Implemented an AES co-processor on a DE1-SoC development board. The project was developed using Verilog and C code within the Quartus Prime II FPGA Software IDE.

#### Data Compression in an Edge Computing Environment using an Auto-Encoder

Created a Python and C-based data compression auto-encoder to evaluate CPU performance and power usage in an edge computing environment, optimizing both compile and runtime processes with various compilers.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Software Development Engineering Intern, Publicis Sapient**

Toronto, Ontario

- Developed a website using Spring Boot, React, and NodeJS to host and manage advertisement campaigns, enabling efficient creation, editing, viewing to be distribution to customers. JUNE 2022 -
  - Utilized Bitbucket, REST, CI/CD Pipelines, Docker, Kubernetes, Microsoft Azure and MongoDB for development and deployment.
  - Contributed to \$1 billion in media sales, collaborating with skilled developers and maintaining partner relationships through Agile-based weekly meetings.

# MAY 2020 -AUGUST 2020

AUGUST 2022

#### **Supply Chain Intern,** Bernstein Diet & Health Clinics

- Tracked medical orders using in-house software, making timely deliveries, and providing usability suggestions.
- Supported IT by collaborating on hardware upgrades, system migrations, and validating new software, while also handling high-order volumes during peak seasons.

# Landscaping/Maintenance Team, Copper Creek

Kleinburg, Ontario

MAY 2020 -SEPTEMBER 2023

- Worked in a senior role within the landscaping team.
- Trained new employees to utilize different equipment and informed fellow coworkers on WHMIS safety measures.

#### **Lifeguard & Swim Instructor,** University of Guelph

Guelph, Ontario

SEPTEMBER 2019 -FEBRUARY 2023

- Ensured the safety of 200+ guests in and around swimming pools, remaining vigilant at all times.
- Provided tailored swimming tips to boost confidence in individuals with limited swimming abilities and resolved conflicts as a leader among lifeguard colleagues.

#### **EDUCATION**

Guelph, Ontario

- SEPTEMBER 2019 -APRIL 2023
- Graduated with High Honours
- Dean's List, 4 consecutive semesters

**Bachelors of Computer Engineering**, University of Guelph